psychtests.com 2019-05-09

# TestYourself by PsychTests: Tests and quizzes on personality, IQ, love/relationships, career, health and attitudes/lifestyle. Professional quality online psychological assessments developed by the web's prominent testing experts.

Privacy Policy

At Testyourself.PsychTests.com, your privacy and peace of mind is our top priority. Your personal information is carefully guarded and will not be sold, rented or otherwise transferred to any third party. 

1 Collection of personally identifiable data

1.1 Declarations of non-use

1.1.1  Supplementation of information from third party sources

1.1.2 Information sharing

_1.1.2.1   Personally Identifiable Data (PII)_

PsychTests does not share any personally identifiable data (PII) with third parties. Only authorized PsychTests employees have access to the user database. Your data may be accessed by our employees to resolve a customer service issue or a billing inquiry. Demographic information may also be accessed automatically by an ad serving software, which uses the information to select ads that are relevant to your interests. The ad serving software accesses this information only to filter available ads and does not record any information other than the number of ads served. 

_1.1.2.2   Aggregate data_

PsychTests compiles aggregate statistics about users. Aggregate demographic information about the site's visitors is available on the website and is typically consulted by advertisers, media and potential business partners. Test data are also analyzed on an aggregate basis. These analyses allow us to fine-tune our assessments and assess their validity and reliability. Only outputs of statistical analyses that use data in an aggregate form are available to third parties. 

_1.1.2.3   Legal disclaimer_

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

1.2 Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or mailing address) on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

1.3 Information Collection Details

1.3.1 User Tracking

_1.3.1.1   Cookies_

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use interactive areas of our site will be very limited.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. See "Third Party Advertisers." This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by PsychTests only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

_1.3.1.2   Anonymous logs_

Like most website, our servers record certain technical information in log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information contained in user profiles. This information is used on aggregate basis to ensure a flawless display of web pages in different browsers and to understand traffic patterns on the site.

_1.3.1.3   Third party advertisers_

The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by third party ad server, our advertising partner. We share Web site usage information about users with a reputable third party for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site. 

Advertising partners use cookies and clear GIFs on this site, which allow it to recognize a user's cookie when a user visits this site. The information that advertising partners collect and share through this technology is not personally identifiable. 

_1.3.1.4   Links to other websites_

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by PsychTests. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. 

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

1.3.2 Registration

Registration is not required to use content on this site. Nevertheless, we encourage you to register for a more personalized experience of the site. Testyourself registered members can also save unfinished tests and store results of all their tests. Regardless of whether you are a registered member or not, upon completing a test, we will show you a "Snapshot" report. At that time, you will be given the option to purchase the Complete report. For registered members both Snapshot reports and Complete reports are automatically saved in the users account, provided he/she is logged in prior to completing the test. For non-registered clients, Snapshot reports are not saved and therefore, need to be converted immediately (prior to leaving the site/page) if a full report is desired.

Receipts are issued for all test purchases made on the site, on a test by test basis. Both registered and non-registered clients can use the transaction number provided on the receipt to retrieve their results. Registered members can also retrieve any purchased results simply by logging into their account and navigating to their saved reports.

_1.3.2.1   Registration form_

What information is collected: PsychTests requires registrants to provide a valid email address, which is used as a unique username, and a self-selected password. In addition, the registration form contains other demographic questions that are optional. The data is stored in a secured database. An automated Registration Confirmation email is sent to the email address you provided during registration

Why: PsychTests uses the information in your profile to: 

  * conduct validation studies on our assessments
  * create a personalized experience on our site by customizing content suggestions to your preferences.
  * analyze the demographic profiles of users in order to better understand our readership base. 
  * to filter out ads that are irrelevant to you and select those that will likely appeal to you. 

How: Data collection is done using a registration form.

Your options: You can fill in the required fields only and skip any questions you are not comfortable answering.

Your control: You can change or remove information from your account at any time. To do so, log into your account, click on "Account Information" in the left navigation menu and modify your information. 

Access: Only authorized PsychTests employees have access to this database. Your data may be accessed to resolve a customer service issue or a billing inquiry. Demographic information may also be accessed automatically by the ad serving software, which uses the information to select ads that are relevant to your interests. The ad serving software accesses this information only to filter available ads and does not record any information other than the number of ads served. 

_1.3.2.2   Forgot password_

What information is collected: The email address used during registration.

Why: To forward your login information to you.

How: Data collection is done using a registration form.

Your options: The email address is a required field in this form and you cannot use this function without entering it.

Your control: You can change your password at any time. To do so, log into your account, click on "Account Information" in the left navigation menu and modify your information. 

Access: Only the person who has access to the registration email address can access the emailed login info.

_1.3.2.3  Storage of user information_

As a general rule, all user and test data are stored in a secured database. Session IDs are stored on the user's computer in the form of cookies. 

1.3.3 Communication 

_1.3.3.1  Contact forms_

What information is collected:

  * All information entered into the online form (some fields may be optional). 
  * Date and time stamp are automatically inserted into the form. 

Why: To resolve a problem you are reporting or respond to your inquiry. 

How: Data collection is done using an online form; the form is sent to our Help desk via email. 

Your options: The name, email address and message text are required fields in this form and you cannot use this function without entering them. You can skip any fields that are not required. 

Access: Our customer service representatives can access any information contained in the emailed form. 

_1.3.3.2  Customer service_

If you communicate with us either by contact forms, regular email or by phone, we will typically respond to you by email. In rare cases when the issue is more complex, we may ask you to provide your phone number in follow-up emails. If you do not wish to communicate by phone, you may indicate your preference in an email message and we will resolve the issue by email.

_1.3.3.3  Confirmation emails_

You will receive a one-time confirmation email after you register an account on this site. You will also receive a confirmation email if you choose to purchase a product or service on our website. You cannot opt out of these communications, as they are an integral part of the registration and purchasing process. 

_1.3.3.4   Service related announcements_

You may receive occasional service-related announcements regarding your account. Such emails may inform you about scheduled downtime of our servers (typically for maintenance and system upgrades), or remind you that your account or certain tests will expire. You cannot opt out of these communications, as they are an integral part of the maintenance of your account. 

1.3.4 Order Forms 

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, etc.) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). 

We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

_1.3.4.1  Security_

All information collected during the payment process is protected using a 128-bit encryption, transferred over secure connections and stored on secure servers. All our servers are monitored 24/7. 

PsychTests processes all payments through secure servers and secure connections to our service providers. Our credit card processing suppliers automatically contact your financial institution to obtain authorization for the purchase. If the transaction is approved, the purchase is completed. 

All data transfers are conducted over encrypted secure networks. Our payment processing suppliers store credit card information associated with all transactions in a secure database. All our suppliers guarantee the confidentiality of all information related to transactions on our sites. 

_1.3.4.2  Purchase logs_

Purchase history and purchase information are stored in a database on a secure server behind a firewall. 

What information is collected:

  * All information entered into the online form (some fields may be optional).
  * A unique transaction number is automatically generated by our payment system service provider upon authorization of the purchase.
  * Your username/email address is automatically recorded. 
  * Date and time stamp is automatically recorded.

Why: To be able to resolve billing inquiries.

How: Payment information is collected through a secure online form ad stored in a database on a secure server. Data are protected using a 128-bit encryption during transfer.

Your options: All fields are required in this form and you cannot make an online purchase without entering them. You can also make a payment by sending us a check or money order. You also have the option to call us or fax us your credit card information (purchases of $50 or more; this option is not available to non-members).

Your control: You can interrupt the payment process at any time before you confirm that you wish to place your order.

Access: Only authorized customer service representatives can access any information contained in the purchase history database.

1.3.5 Tests

The extensive battery of psychological tests is PsychTest's signature feature. Information gathered from test-takers allows us to conduct scientific studies, validate our assessments and fine-tune them based on the results and conclusions drawn from the statistical analyses.

All test questions must be answered before the test can be scored. At some point during the test administration, you may receive a Validation study form. This is a set of demographic and psychographic questions that are not used to score the test; rather, this information serves as a benchmark of a specific characteristic (also called a criterion measure). We then statistically analyze the test and the validation information to see how well the test scores predict the criterion.

What information is collected:

  * All answers entered into the online questionnaire form (answers to all questions administered to you are required to score the test). 
  * All information entered into the Validation study form (all optional). 
  * If you are logged into your account, your username/email address is automatically recorded. If you are not logged in, you are considered to be a "guest".
  * Session ID is recorded.
  * IP number is recorded.
  * Date and time stamp are automatically recorded. 

Why: To conduct scientific studies, validate our assessments and publish articles with our findings on the website and in scientific literature.

How: Data collection is done using an online form; the data are stored in a database.

Your options: If you wish to take a test anonymously, you can take it as a guest (without logging into your account). The report of any test taken anonymously will not be saved (unless purchased) but test data will be recorded for statistical purposes. You have the option to participate in our validation study by answering a set of questions that are not part of the assessment. If you don't wish to participate, simply skip the validation questions. 

Your control: You can change or remove information from your account at any time. To do so, log into your account, click on "Account Information" in the left navigation menu and modify your information. 

Access: Authorized database administrators have access to all data stored in our databases. Authorized customer service representatives access your data if a problem with your account is reported. Our statisticians and psychologists have access to the data sets. All data are treated anonymously. Aggregated results and conclusions drawn from the data are distributed to the psychological community and general public. 

2 Business transitions

In the event PsychTests goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. 

3 Changes in privacy policy 

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you on the Privacy Policy page, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.
